Sculptors Guild
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Sculptors Guild records
1936-1979
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Sculptors Guild (New York, N. Y.)
5.7 linear feet
The records of the Sculptors Guild measure 5.7 linear feet, date from 1936-1979, and document the history of this non-profit artist organization from its inception in 1937 to the late 1970s. The records contain correspondence and minutes documenting the activities of the Guild's various committees, legal and financial records, artist files for Guild members, exhibition files, printed material, scrapbooks and photographs.
Historical Note
The Sculptors Guild was founded in New York City in 1937 by a group of artists interested in the promotion of contemporary sculpture in a wide variety of styles through free group exhibitions and educational programs. Membership in the Guild was obtainable only by invitation, based on a sculptor's creative ability and professional standing.
The Guild held annual exhibitions of contemporary sculpture in locations such as the terrace of the International Building at Rockefeller Plaza, Bryant Park, the New York Botanical Gardens, and perhaps most notably at Lever House, marking the introduction of the exhibition of professional art in corporate lobbies. The Guild frequently combined demonstrations and lectures with its exhibitions. Many traveling exhibitions circulated under the auspices of the American Federation of Arts, the Carnegie Corporation, and the Board of Education of the City of New York. The Guild also held several outdoor exhibitions in various other locations in New York City, and at the New York World's Fair in 1939-1940.
Between 1937 and 1964 the Sculptors Guild was supported by membership dues, a 30 percent commission taken on sales of sculpture at annual exhibibitions and private funding. In the mid-1960s the Guild recognized the need for increased funding from foundations and established the Friends of the Sculptors Guild to this end.
The Sculptors Guild was headquartered at various New York locations throughout its history. From 1937-1938, it was located at 52 West 8th Street, moving in early 1939 to 37 East 4th Street. Later that year the Guild moved again, to 96 Fifth Avenue, where it stayed for 25 years. In 1966 the Guild moved to 106 West 16th Street and, in the following year, to 797 Madison Avenue. In 1991 the Guild was located at 35 East 85th Street. The Sculptors Guild is still in operation in 2005 and is located at the Soho Building, 110 Greene Street, New York City.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Sculptors Guild measure 5.7 linear feet, date from 1936-1979, and document the history of this non-profit artist organization from its inception in 1937 to the late 1970s. The records contain correspondence and minutes documenting the activities of the Guild's various committees, legal and financial records, artist files for Guild members, exhibition files, printed material, scrapbooks and photographs.
The early years of the Guild's history, from 1938-1948, are particularly well documented in business records including detailed meeting minutes of the executive board, membership and nominating committees, and exhibition and cultural committees. Correspondence files provide a good overview of the development of Guild programs and changes within the organization from 1937-1976, although coverage of events from the late 1940s to the mid 1960s is relatively sparse. Researchers should consult subseries 1.2: Correspondence by Subject, for records relating to this period.
Artist files provide biographical information for and photographs of many of the Guild's members. Scrapbooks, exhibition files and printed material document the founding of the Guild and its exhibitions from the late 1930s to the 1970s. The collection also contains photographs of Guild members, officers and many of its exhibitions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1937-1976 (Boxes 1, 9, OV 10; 1.0 linear foot)
Series 2: Business Records, 1936-1974 (Boxes 2-3; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 3: Artist Files, 1936-circa 1965 (Boxes 3-4, 7; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, circa 1938-1979 (Boxes 4, 9, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Scrapbooks, 1938-1952 (Boxes 7-9; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Material, circa 1938-1974 (Boxes 5-6, OV 10; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, circa 1938, circa 1960s (Box 6; 1 folder)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects-Topical:
Sculpture, American--Societies, etc.; Sculpture, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Sculptors--United States
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Scrapbooks
Provenance
The Sculptors Guild records were donated by the Sculptors Guild in 1966, 1979, and 1991 and were microfilmed on Reels D262-D266A and 5908-5910 in the order in which they were received.
Restrictions on Access
Collection is partially microfilmed. Use of material not microfilmed requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels D262-D266A and 5908-5910 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the current archival arrangement of material does not necessarily correspond to the order on microfilm. Where possible microfilm reel and frame numbers have been provided in the Series Description/Container Listing.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1937-1976, Series 1:; (Boxes 1, 9, OV 10; 1.0 linear foot)
  This series contains correspondence between members of the Sculptors Guild and documents the Guild's interactions with museums, galleries, patrons and honorary sponsors. The series provides a good overview of program developments and documents issues such as funding and the decision to seek increased donations from foundations in the mid-1960s with the formation of Friends of the Sculptors Guild. Notable correspondents include Juliana Force, Leon Kroll, Hugo Robus, William Talbot, and William Zorach.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  1.1: Chronological Correspondence, 1937-1976
  1.2: Correspondence by Subject, 1938-1961
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1937-1976, 1.1:
    - Correspondence, 1937-1948, (19 folders; Reel D262L 1-922; Reel D266A: 116-156; Reel 5908: 11-760) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1957, (Reel D262: 1-922; Reel D266A: 116-156; Reel 5908: 11-760) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964, (Reel D262: 1-922; Reel D266A: 116-156; Reel 5908: 11-760) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1976, (14 folders; see also Box 9, OV 10; Reel D262: 1-922; Reel D266A: 116-156; Reel 5908: 11-760) (Box 1)
    - Oversized Floor Plan of Exhibition Enclosed with Letter, 1966, (Reel 5908: 497) (Box 9 (sol))
    - Blueprint of First Floor, Two Lincoln Square, Enclosed with Letter, 1975, (blueprint not microfilmed; letter on Reel 5908: 744) (Box OV 10)
  - Correspondence by Subject, 1938-1961, 1.2:
    - Artists for Victory, 1942-1945, (Reel D262: 1-22) (Box 1)
    - Consulates, 1942, (Reel D262: 23-47) (Box 1)
    - General, 1940-1961, undated, (9 folders; Reel D262: 48-227) (Box 1)
    - Museums and Galleries, 1938-1942, (17 folders; Reel D262: 306-763) (Box 1)
    - Patrons, 1944, (Reel D262: 764-805) (Box 1)
    - Sculpture Information Sources, 1938-1942, (2 folders; Reel D262: 258-305) (Box 1)
    - Secretary, 1942-1944, (4 folders; Reel D262: 806-872) (Box 1)
    - WPA Supporters, 1938-1939, (Reel D262: 873-922) (Box 1)
- Business Records, 1936-1974, Series 2:; (Boxes 2-3; 1.6 linear feet)
  The Guild's business records document the founding and early history of the Guild and it's continued operation through the minutes of the organization's various committees, membership records, publicity files, and financial and legal records.
  This series is arranged as 4 subseries:
  2.1: Minutes and Membership, 1936-1974
  2.2: Committee Files, 1938-1956
  2.3: Publicity Files, 1939-1960
  2.4: Financial and Legal Records, 1938-1972
  - Minutes and Membership, 1936-1974, 2.1:
    This subseries documents membership in the Guild through biographical accounts of members, membership lists and the minutes of meetings relating to fund-raising and the membership recruiting activities of the organization.
    Also found here are minutes of the Guild's various committees. One set of minutes for October 1938-May 1941 has been left in it's original collation although it is duplicated elsewhere in the subseries. Minutes include those for the executive board meetings, general membership and membership admission meetings, and meetings of the ways and means committee, exhibition committee, cultural committee, grounds and publicity commitee, and nominating committee.
    The founding and early history of the Guild is documented in a statement of aims and purposes, correspondence relating to incorporation, and a 1940 typescript of the history of the Sculptors Guild. Reorganization correspondence deals with changes to membership requirements and reorganizations within the Guild.
    - Art and Skills Corps, American Red Cross, 1942-1943, (Reel D264: 534-553) (Box 2)
    - Biographical Accounts of Members, 1937-1940, (Reel D264: 582-603) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Honorary Sponsors, 1942-1949, (Reel D264: 448-553) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Reorganization, 1939-1946, 1960, (Reel D264: 1345-1351) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Reorganization, Acknowledgment Cards, 1946, (Reel D264: 1309-1344) (Box 2)
    - Letters to Members, 1944-1959, (Reel D264: 999-1030) (Box 2)
    - Lists of Officers and Members, 1939-1942 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1936-1947, (8 folders; Reel D266A, Reel 5908) (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1966-1974, (2 folders; Reel D266A, Reel 5908) (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 18 October 1938-25 May 1939, (Reel D266A) (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 10 October 1939-28 May 1941, (Reel D266A) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1938-1954, (2 folders; Reel 5908: 1419-1433, Reel 5909: 12-40) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Reports and Memoranda (not Sculptors Guild), 1939-1958, (Reel D264: 1352-1413; Reel D265: 1-26) (Box 2)
    - Raffle Party, 1940-1942, (Reel D264: 394-447) (Box 2)
    - Statement of Aims and Purposes and Incorporation Correspondence, 1936-1937, (Reel D266A: 1-18) (Box 2)
    - Typescript History of the Sculptors Guild, 1940, (Reel D266A: 157-159) (Box 2)
  - Committee Files, 1938-1956, 2.2:
    This subseries documents the activities of the Cultural Committee and the Exhibition Committee. Minutes for these two committees have been left with the Guild's other minutes in 2.1: Minutes and Membership, in order to retain their context as business records of the Guild as a whole.
    Cultural committee files document the activities of the book comittee in addition to correspondence inlcluding letters from José DeCreeft, Chaim Gross, Paul Manship, and Maurice Sterne.
    Exhibition committee files contain correspondence including a letter from David Smith, copyright records, notes, a guest book, photographs, and printed material concerning exhibitions with which the Sculptors Guild was involved. Outdoor exhibition photographs include four photographs of Helen Keller visiting an exhibition accompanied by William Zorach, and photographs of singer Dusolina Giannini, actress Aline MacMahon, and artists Mark Friedman, Hugo Robus, Concetta Scaravaglione, and Louis Slobodkin.
    Miscellaneous exhibition files contain correspondence, notes, printed material, photographs and several unidentified sketches. Additionional records documenting Sculptors Guild exhibitions can be found in Series 4: Exhibition Files.
    - Cultural Committee Files, 1938-1941, 2.2.1:
      - Book Committee, Correspondence, 1938-1941, undated, (Reel D262) (Box 2)
      - Book Committee, Notes and Writings, 1938, undated, (Reel D262) (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1939-1941, (Reel D262: 1027-1050) (Box 2)
      - Questionnaires, 1941, (Reel D262: 1051-1101) (Box 2)
    - Exhibition Committee Files, 2.2.2:
      - Copyright Records, 1939-1941, (Reel D264: 325-340) (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1940-1942, (Reel D262) (Box 2)
      - Correspondence and Notes, 1942, (Reel D262) (Box 2)
      - Exhibition Guest Book, 1942-1955, (Reel D264: 341-393) (Box 2)
      - National Art Week, 1939-1941, (Reel D262: 1250-1305) (Box 2)
      - Outdoor Exhibition (Box 2)
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1941, (2 folders; Reel D263: 890-941) (Box 2)
        - Correspondence Regarding Loans, 1942, (Reel D263) (Box 2)
        - General Records, 1938-1941, (Reel D263) (Box 2)
        - Publicity, 1939-1944, (Reel D263) (Box 2)
        - Photographs, 1938-1941, undated, (Reel D263) (Box 2)
      - Traveling Exhibition (Box 2)
        - Artist Biographical Accounts, 1940-1941, (4 folders; Reel D263: 714-742) (Box 2)
        - Committee Minutes and Notes, 1939-1941, (Reel D263) (Box 2)
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1939-1944, (2 folders; Reel D263) (Box 3)
        - Correspondence, Carnegie Corporation, 1939-1940, (Reel D263: 692-713) (Box 3)
        - Exhibition Entries, 1940-1941, (Reel D263) (Box 3)
        - Financial Records, 1939-1941, (Reel D263: 1045-1067) (Box 3)
        - Galleys for Catalogs for 1940-1941 Exhibition, 1940, (Reel D263: 743-751) (Box 3)
        - Publicity, 1939-1940, (Reel D263: 1111-1114) (Box 3)
        - Photographs, circa 1940-1941, undated, (Reel D263) (Box 3)
      - World's Fair Exhibition (Box 3)
        - Correspondence, 1940, (Reel D263: 1207-1260) (Box 3)
        - Notes, 1940, (Reel D263: 1261-1276) (Box 3)
        - Publicity, 1940, (Reel D263) (Box 3)
        - Photographs, 1940, (Reel D263) (Box 3)
      - Proposed International Exhibition, Correspondence, 1942, (2 folders; Reel D264: 1-155) (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous Exhibitions, 1951-1954, (2 folders; Reel D264) (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous Exhibitions, Photographs, 1942-1956, undated, (Reel D264) (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous Exhibitions, Photographs of Celita Vaccani (Brazilian Sculptor), 1955, (Reel D264) (Box 3)
  - Publicity Files, 1939-1946, 1960, 2.3:
    This subseries contains publicity-related correspondence, notices to members and press releases. Press releases and notes include a transcript of a radio interview with Ann V. Horton and Thomas Cheney from January 1941. There is also a folder of records documenting a tour of member studios from 1966.
    - Correspondence, 1939-1942, (Reel D264) (Box 3)
    - Notices to Members, 1939-1960, (Reel D264) (Box 3)
    - Press Releases and Notes, 1942-circa 1959, undated, (Reel D264) (Box 3)
    - Tour of Guild Member Studios, 1966, (Reel 5908: 1395-1418) (Box 3)
  - Financial and Legal Records, 1938-1972, 2.4:
    This series includes correspondence of the treasurer and financial reports in addition to general financial records of the Sculptors Guild including documentation of sculpture loans and sales, contracts, a ledger of expenditures, price lists and banking records.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Banking Records, 1939-1942, (Reel 5908: 853-879) (Box 3)
    - Check Register, 1946-1948, (Reel 5908: 880-925) (Box 3)
    - Contracts, 1938-1952, (Reel 5908: 764-785) (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, Treasurer, 1941-1943, (Reel D265: 135-225) (Box 3)
    - Financial Reports, 1938-1946, 1956-1957, 1966, (Reel D265: 47-134) (Box 3)
    - Insurance Records, 1967-1970, (Reel 5908: 799-813) (Box 3)
    - Leases, 1940-1970, (Reel 5908: 786-798) (Box 3)
    - Ledger, 1967, (Reel 5908: 926-942) (Box 3)
    - Lists of Foundations, circa 1966 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Legal Documents, 1939-1940, (D266A: 360-365) (Box 3)
    - Price Lists, 1970-1972, undated, (Reel 5908: 943-953) (Box 3)
    - Receipts, National City Bank of New York, 1942, (Reel 5908: 835-852) (Box 3)
    - Receipts, Petty Cash, 1941-1967, undated, (Reel 5908: 966-993) (Box 3)
    - Sales Records, 1967, (Reel 5908: 954-965) (Box 3)
    - Tax Records, 1960-1968, (Reel 5908: 814-834) (Box 3)
- Artist Files, circa 1938-1979, Series 3:; (Boxes 4, 9, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet)
  Artist files contain biographical accounts, photographs, and printed material concerning individual members of the Sculptors Guild. Many of the files contain at least one photograph of the artist including files for: Saul Baizerman, Richmond Barthé, Simone Brangier Boas, Richard Davis, Eugenie Gershoy, Minna Harkavy, Nathaniel Kaz, Henry Kreis, Paul Manship, Ward Montague, Hugo Robus, Charles Rudy, Concetta Scaravaglione, David Smith, Mary Tarleton, Heinz Warneke, and Adolf Wolff. The file for Enrico Glicenstein contains a photograph of Glicenstein and his son, painter Emanuel Romano.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by name of artist.
  - Baizerman, Saul, 1938-1939, undated, (Reel D265: 226-266; Reel 5909: 42-48) (Box 3)
  - Barret, Oliver O'Connor, 1951, undated, (Reel D265: 268-311; Reel 5909: 49-55) (Box 3)
  - Barthé, Richmond, 1938-1939, undated, (Reel D265: 312-368) (Box 3)
  - Boas, Simone Brainger, circa 1939-1940, undated, Reel D265: 312-313, 369-396; Reel 5909: 56-62 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Sonia Gordon, 1938-1939, undated, (Reel D265: 397-439; Reel 5909: 63-75) (Box 3)
  - Caesar, Doris, undated, (Reel D265: 440-457) (Box 3)
  - Cash, Harold, 1936, undated, (Reel D265: 427, 458-476; Reel 5909: 76-80) (Box 3)
  - Cavallito, Albino, undated, (Reel D265: 477-483; Reel 5909: 81-83) (Box 3)
  - Chapin, Cornelia Van Auken, undated, (Reel D265: 484-491; Reel 5909: 84-86) (Box 3)
  - Cronbach, Robert, undated, (Reel D265: 492-494) (Box 3)
  - Cross, Louise, undated, (Reel D265: 495-509, 512-546; Reel 5909: 87-103) (Box 3)
  - Cullen, Lilliana, undated, (Reel 5909: 104-109) (Box 3)
  - Cunliffe, Mitzi, undated, (Reel D265: 547-548) (Box 3)
  - Davis, Richard, 1938-circa 1940, undated, (Reel D265: 549-576; Reel 5909: 107-109) (Box 3)
  - Decker, Alice, undated, (Reel D265: 577-610; Reel 5909: 110-117) (Box 3)
  - De Creeft, Joseph, undated, (Reel D265: 611-615) (Box 3)
  - De Marco, Jean, undated, (Reel D265: 616, 808) (Box 3)
  - Diedrich, Hunt, undated, (Reel 5909: 110-121) (Box 3)
  - Epstein, Jacob, undated, (Reel D265: 623-624) (Box 3)
  - Ferber, Herbert, undated, (Reel D265: 625-630) (Box 3)
  - Fiene, Paul, 1938, undated, (Reel D265: 631-635) (Box 3)
  - Flanagan, John B., undated, (Reel D265: 636-637; Reel 5909: 122-125) (Box 3)
  - Freilicher, Hy, undated, (Reel D265: 638-639) (Box 3)
  - Friedman, Mark, undated, (Reel D265: 640-645) (Box 3)
  - Geissbuhler, Arnold, undated, (Reel D265: 646-671; Reel 5909: 126-127) (Box 3)
  - Gershoy, Eugenie, undated, (Reel D265: 672-690; Reel 5909: 128-129) (Box 3)
  - Glicenstein, Enrico, 1939-1940, undated, (Reel D265: 691-735; Reel 5909: 130-137) (Box 4)
  - Glickman, Maurice, undated, (Reel D265: 736-739) (Box 4)
  - Goodelman, Aaron J., undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 740-743) (Box 4)
  - Greenbaum, Dorothea, undated, (Reel D265: 744-746) (Box 4)
  - Gross, Chaim, 1961, undated, (Reel D265: 747-753) (Box 4)
  - Harkavy, Minna, 1938, undated, (Reel D265: 754-758; Reel 5909: 138-140) (Box 4)
  - Hauser, Alonzo, circa 1938, undated, (Reel D265: 759-778) (Box 4)
  - Hebald, Milton, circa 1939, undated, (Reel D265: 779-804) (Box 4)
  - Horn, Milton, undated, (Reel D265: 805-807) (Box 4)
  - Hovannes, John, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 809-813) (Box 4)
  - Hyun, Paul, 1937-1941, undated, (Reel D265: 814-837; Reel 5909: 145-147) (Box 4)
  - Johnston, Randolph W., undated, (Reel D265: 838-839) (Box 4)
  - Kane, Margaret Brassler, 1943, (Reel 5909: 148-158) (Box 4)
  - Kaz, Nathaniel, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 840-854) (Box 4)
  - King, William, undated, (Reel D265: 855-856) (Box 4)
  - Konenkov, Sergei, undated, (Reel D265: 857-858) (Box 4)
  - Kreis, Henry, undated, (Reel D265: 859-862) (Box 4)
  - Landis, Lily, 1961, undated, (Reel D265: 863-866) (Box 4)
  - Lednicka, Maryla, undated, (Reel 5909: 148-158) (Box 4)
  - Lipton, Seymour, undated, (Reel D265: 867-868) (Box 4)
  - LoMedico, Thomas G., undated, (Reel D265: 869-870) (Box 4)
  - Lux, Gwen, undated, (Reel D265: 871-872) (Box 4)
  - Maldarelli, Oronzio, 1940, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 873-954; Reel 5909: 155-158) (Box 4)
  - Manship, Paul, circa 1939, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 955-963) (Box 4)
  - Margoulies, Berta, circa 1938, undated, (Reel D265: 964-973) (Box 4)
  - Melicov, Dina, undated, (Reel D265: 974-979) (Box 4)
  - Michnick, David, undated, (Reel D265: 980-989) (Box 4)
  - Miller, Burr, undated, (Reel D265: 989-1027; Reel 5909: 159-161) (Box 4)
  - Montague, Ward, circa 1940, undated, (Reel D265: 1028-1051; Reel 5909: 162-175) (Box 4)
  - Nicholas, S., undated, (Reel D265: 1052-1053) (Box 4)
  - Nunez del Prado, Marina, undated, (Reel D265: 617-622) (Box 4)
  - Renouf, Edward, circa 1960s, (Reel 5909: 176-190) (Box 4)
  - Robus, Hugo, 1938, undated, (Reel D265: 1054-1093; Reel 5909: 181-183) (Box 4)
  - Rudy, Charles, 1939, undated, (Reel D265: 1094-1115) (Box 4)
  - Russin, Robert I., undated, (Reel D265: 1116-1140; Reel 5909: 187-190) (Box 4)
  - Sardeau, Helene, circa 1941, undated, (Reel D265: 1141-1144) (Box 4)
  - Scarvaglione, Concetta, circa 1939, undated, (Reel D265: 1145-1175; Reel 5909: 191-194) (Box 4)
  - Slobodkin, Louis, 1939, (see Box 7; Reel D265: 1176) (Box 4)
  - Smith, David, circa 1940, undated, (Reel D265: 1177-1188) (Box 4)
  - Stea, Cesare, undated, (Reel D265: 1189-1253; Reel 5909: 195-196) (Box 4)
  - Sterne, Maurice, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D265: 1254-1264; Reel 5909: 197-202) (Box 4)
  - Tarleton, Mary, 1940, undated, (Reel D265: 1264-1285) (Box 4)
  - Teller, June, circa 1961, (Reel D265: 1286-1287) (Box 4)
  - Umlauf, Charles, 1951, undated, (Reel D265: 1288-1332; Reel 5909: 203-207) (Box 4)
  - Vagis, Polygnotos G., undated, (Reel D265: 1333-1341; Reel 5909: 208-212) (Box 4)
  - Vodicka, Ruth, circa 1965, undated, (Reel 5909: 203-216) (Box 4)
  - Walsh, Bernard, undated, (Reel D265: 1342-1357) (Box 4)
  - Walton, Marion, undated (Box 4)
  - Warneke, Heinz, circa 1951, undated, (Reel D265: 1358-1361; Reel 5909: 222-224) (Box 4)
  - Werner, Nat, undated, (Reel 5909: 217-227) (Box 4)
  - Weschler, Anita, undated, (Reel D265: 1362-1365) (Box 4)
  - Wheelock, Warren, circa 1936-circa 1947, undated, (Reel D265: 1366-1399; Reel 5909: 228-243) (Box 4)
  - Wolff, Adolf, circa 1939, undated, (Reel D265: 510-511; Reel D266: 1-34; Reel 5909: 244-250) (Box 4)
  - Zadkine, Ossip, circa 1942, (Reel D266: 35-36) (Box 4)
  - Zorach, William, undated, (see also Box 7; Reel D266: 37-39) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous and Unidentified, Photos of Artwork, circa 1932, undated (Box 4)
  - Bazierman, Saul, Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 263) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Goodelman, Aaron J., Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 742-743) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Hovannes, John, Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 809) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Kaz, Nathaniel, Photographs of Artwork, 1931-1939, (Reel D265: 846-854) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Maldarelli, Oronzio, Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 952-953) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Manship, Paul, Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 962-963) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Slobodkin, Louis, Photograph of Artwork, 1939, (Reel D265: 1176) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Sterne, Maurice, Photographs Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 1258-1261) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Zorach, William, Photograph of Artwork, undated, (Reel D265: 39) (Box 7 (sol))
- Exhibition Files, circa 1938-1979, Series 4:; (Boxes 4, 9, OV 10; 0.5 linear feet)
  This series documents Guild exhibitions through correspondence, notes, printed matter and photographs. Additional material related to exhibitions can be found in 2.2.2: Exhibition Committee Files.